If anyone who's predicting what looks
like in a year or two is going to be
fundamentally wrong. We don't know where
we're going other than that we do know
that we're going to keep building
software while maintaining billions if
not trillions of lines of code that are
already out there. A lot of these coding
agents are actually really good at
brainstorming. And so a lot of my
developers are using cloud code to write
code but before they do that they also
use cloud code to brainstorm. And I
don't see that going to be replaced
anytime [music] soon.
>> How do you envision the job of a future
AI native developer? The biggest skill
as a software developer as an engineer
is that you know I think you're going to
see more of a agent to agent
collaboration. What's really interesting
about that right now is it gives me as a
human feedback on code now, but if that
code was written by Devon, why do you
give that feedback to me, give it to
Devon and have Devon figure out that is
how you would do that in a human to
human developer team, right?
>> What can you say about your new startup
and what made you sort of take the leap
from from where you kind of were in
GitHub? I think that's the
Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast's for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So, if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. All
right, back to the episode.
>> Hello everyone. Uh, welcome back to the
AI Native podcast. Uh, today we have a
really exciting guest that, you know,
I've known for quite a while here. Uh,
we've managed to juggle schedules to,
uh, to make work. And that's Thomas
Donke, uh, who is, uh, who until
recently was the CEO of GitHub, uh, and
is now we'll talk about this in sort of
the brave AI dev, uh, sort of startup
land on it. Thomas, thanks for coming on
to the show.
>> Hey guy and thanks so much for having
me.
>> Um, so uh Thomas, it's it's sort of
funny a little bit as we connected here
or like know reconnected. we've been
sort of chatting throughout the time. uh
talked a little bit about uh how we how
we met uh initially and this was was
actually like it's not sort of hasn't
been publicly discussed but there was a
moment in which it looked like GitHub
might acquire sneak uh early in the
journey uh and I guess that's how we uh
we got in a room uh and you know clearly
clearly kind of led to uh to interesting
paths as uh as GitHub got pretty big in
uh in sort of apps space on it clearly
didn't happen on the snick side which
worked out pretty well uh but uh yeah
those are like fun and intense convers
conversation. There was a way to start a
relationship there.
>> Yeah. So for the you know for the
listener to have some context uh it was
summer 2018 to my memory. Um so
Microsoft already announced uh that we
would be acquiring GitHub. Um I was part
of that acquisition team together with
Ned Freiedman who then became the CEO of
GitHub and a few other folks. Mario
Rodriguez who's now the head of product
for GitHub. And as we had signed the
deal we were like thinking what else
would be a strategic for for the GitHub
portfolio product and our platform. uh
to to be added to and we had a long list
of interesting startups in the space and
and one of them was was Sneak. So to my
memory we had you over in uh the Twitter
building uh funny enough where where
back then Ned's office was um and in the
conference room we chat a little bit of
>> you know how your business is going and
uh how the you know open source security
space is important for GitHub as a
platform and obviously for for sneak as
as a product and that's how we how we
met the first time.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I remember I like remember
the conversation very vividly on it. We
also we dragged Nat at some point I
think it was before that actually to
come speak at our all hands uh at uh at
a sneak all hands as he was sort of
exploring possibilities and it was
interesting you were in that sort of
annoying window in which you couldn't
act you could just explore because you
were sort of waiting for the GitHub
acquisition to uh to close and in the
meantime investors swooped in and uh and
gave us like you know higher valuation
uh opportunities in it and
>> and it was sort of been fun times
clearly both kind of worked out pretty
well like you know GitHub built a
thriving security business. Sneakers
have grown well. Uh
>> well, you know, if you could time travel
back to 2018 and tell both of us what
the valuations of developer tools
startups are in 2025. You know, in 2018,
everybody thought the 7.5 billion price
tag for GitHub was high and the
valuation for Sneak was was growing
quite fast and there were a number of
other companies that felt quote unquote
overpriced. Uh in in today's world,
that's that's almost a seed round.
[laughter]
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And uh and um I think you know there's
so much excitement and we'll get to that
later in the part but there's so much
excitement in the space that um uh
people now believe that developer tools
companies can become much bigger than
than back in 2018.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I fully fully agree and I
guess kind of you know part of it is the
sort of the software is hitting the
world but also just a bunch of uh you
know like more developers and and just
sort of better learnings about how to
turn I think a bunch of these tools that
were just described in like technical
terms into uh into kind of real business
value right and uh so maybe it's just
the software is eating the world kind of
trend you know manifesting uh and it's
all inevitable. So I guess you're you're
back in the sort of the uh the sort of
the startup uh reality of it you know
after uh after GitHub um and you know a
lot of the conversation when I sort of
hearken back to to that moment was on
kind of startups versus incumbents right
you sort of have the large companies
kind of coming along have all the
distributions you know in the security
context for instance GitHub eventually
acquired and launched dependabot uh on
it and clearly you can now kind of you
know flip a switch and suddenly all the
repos get uh uh you know get this
functionality which is this like massive
power on it. uh and and yet kind of kind
of common wisdom is that sort of
startups are uh are where innovation
happens, right? And you kind of you
learn the breakthroughs happen in sort
of startup land on it. The incumbents
come along and I was curious like you
know you're you were sort of in the sort
of the heart of it, you know, from uh
from the sort of the incumbent land in
GitHub. Uh and now you're you're kind of
going back to startup. I guess what's
what's the the view you've you've you've
built up in terms of where innovation
will come from in this world? like
you're you is it still sort of the
startups will uh will innovate or are
incumbents kind of clued in enough that
they will that you actually expect uh a
bunch of the a bunch of the innovations
and stuff to come from there?
>> We see innovation everywhere, right?
Like it's it's both the startup world
and the incumbents kind of trying to out
innovate uh each other. Um, I'd love,
you know, to think about competition in
business as very similar to competition
in sports. Yeah.
>> And you have, you know, a leader, um,
you know, right now, uh, uh, in Formula
1, it's now McLaren, but for like the
last four years it was Red Bull, right?
Right. And so that's effectively the
incumbent and they have the challenge of
staying on top of the game and they get
the best people, you know, poached off
to other teams because they have a
career path there and can become, you
know, the team boss while at at Red Bull
they were kind of like stuck under the
stuck quote unquote, you know, under the
under the previous team boss. And the
same is true in in our industry. There's
the the big ones uh that make a lot of
revenue. And I think it's it's it's easy
to forget, you know, when you're in the
startup land or when you're looking at
these two worlds that the the big
companies, they fight a very different
uh uh battle, you know, if if if you,
you know, uh want to grow a Microsoft at
double digit percentages every year,
that's like, you know, double digit
billions of dollars um that that have to
be added that net new, right? Like on
top of the renewals um as everything,
you know, these days is a SAS business
or like a recurring revenue business.
And so it's a very different game if you
have to find 30 40 billion in net new
revenue uh versus your small startup
that is happy when they get to the first
you know one two or or or 10 million in
revenue run rate. I think that's number
one is like you got to realize that
these they're not fighting in the same
you know weight class in boxing they're
fighting in very different classes and
the so but then you know when you look
into the what they're actually building
the products and the features it's it's
actually in the same space and I think
that's really what makes this so
interesting and you see the big
companies you know all adding AI
features and building agents and and
pushing really hard and and staying you
know in the news and then in the middle
kind of like are the AI studios like
like open and tropic and then there even
there that's big different sizes of of
these studios, right? From really big
like open air to to quite small and and
somewhere in the middle is Mistral and
and Black Forest Labs and what have you.
And then there's the, you know,
companies that that are completely new
and they're building with these AI tools
what you might call AI native, you know,
from the start. And I think that's a
very, you know, uh, exciting space
because effectively, you know, as as a
dev, uh, you start your morning not by
going into Jira or if you're, if you're
more lucky, get up issues and if you're
even more lucky, maybe it's linear. Uh,
you you go and open a terminal and you
open cloud code or or AMP or Gemini CLI
and um you you kind of like brainstorm
with the agent as the first step, right?
And so that's a very different way of
working than if you're in an existing
codebase in a large company uh where you
have a lot of sneak findings that you
have to work through. You have your
product manager backlog. You know you
have your technical debt. You have your
on call rotation and so I think both of
these sites will innovate in their own
ways and it will be really interesting
of who can you know change the world
faster. Yeah, I think it's I really like
the sort of the lens on the sort of the
the dollar count and I think it's one of
those that gets a little bit challenged
I think with AI with just the level of
attention, right? because it was uh our
CTO at Akami uh before founding Sneak
and you know as we were sort of building
business cases over there it was
immediately like yeah can this be you
know a fairly instant within the next
couple years at least like$und00 million
AR business because otherwise you know
it's kind of hard to really rationalize
it within the the system and so that
definitely opens that window for
companies to to build up and prove out
that a business will become you know
that that size but it seems like in AI
there's kind of this uh uh sort of sense
that, you know, things can become a
billion-dollar business in such a short
window of time that that bets are legit,
you know, to make even within the
incumbents. No, like, you know, I think
that feels a little bit different now
than it did in the in the traditional
kind of a startup versus incumbent
reality.
>> I think it is and it isn't. um you know
and the revenue the revenue numbers or
you know the enterprise sales motion is
also often used as an excuse
>> you know that you don't focus on the
product anymore and you're accepting
that the user experience sucks um
>> uh you know I was I won't call out the
the product I was trying to set up SSO
for you know a a tool that we want to
use within with a new my new startup and
>> uh I couldn't figure out how to do that
and it's it's like you would think
that's an easy thing these days to just
connect your your Google identity and
and have SSO for everybody. Um, and I'm
sure you know somebody has a reason why
it is the way it is. And the challenge
that we all fighting is that we have not
enough uh time in our days. And u so
everything you know whether it's Netflix
and YouTube, whether it's work, um
whether it's you know real life things
like Lego has become a a battle about uh
your wake time uh and you can only
reduce your sleep time so much until
until things that's really unhealthy,
right? battling time and at work that
means priorities setting priorities and
then I think again this is much easier
at a startup even more so if you don't
have a customer yet right like I was uh
I for the my new company is fully remote
so everybody is somewhere around the
world and we recently met uh for the
first time together in person in
Singapore and one of my open remarks was
like this is the going to be the most
happiest time in our in this company
life because we have no customers we
have no production system nobody is on
call you We we're just prototyping
and being creative and so looking back
you know in a few years this will look
like the happy time because in in a year
from now hopefully you know we have you
know a product out there and we have
found some customers and maybe they or
even paying us some money and then the
life is very different because then you
have to prioritize between the thing you
want to do and the thing that actually
is driving the business and that's what
really big companies uh or companies
that have found you know some form of
product market fit are fighting every
single day and
>> and Um AI is shifting that I think to
some degree because agents allow you to
take over things that you don't want to
do you know so you have more time for
the things that you do want to do. I
think you know security findings you
know you mentioned dependabot uh uh
those kind of things will get even
easier because an agent can just solve
that for you to the degree where you
only have to approve at the end that
it's ready to deploy um you know
cleaning up you know tech debt. Um, I
have the the VIPE coding book here from
from Gene Kim and Steve Jagger and and
it has a lot of these anecdotes in there
like how they're going into like I think
it's 25 30 year old codebase and all of
a sudden they're burning through the
issues that they never had any
motivation to pick up and and that
ultimately then means you have more time
uh to to build to build something cool.
Yeah, I think I I relate to the sort of
the speed uh kind of more maybe than the
business model specifically in AI like I
think I think that is a change uh and
and to be able to build a business in a
native mode. I I love the I referred to
the first sort of uh you know months
maybe I guess of Tesla's run as like the
honeymoon period because you know like
because reality hasn't hit you in the
face yet. You know you're you're uh you
know you get to build those and you know
but nobody has sort of told you your
product sucks yet. You know nobody told
you this is technically in feasible on
it. I guess there's an there's an
exception to that. I think both you and
I were in a kind of privileged place in
terms of ability to fund raise. So
there's like you know not all founders
are kind of in that reality. But once
you pass the fund raise uh then uh then
those are good. Uh although you do
there's something amazing about users
telling you your product is amazing. Uh
and you know that's are very satisfying
and so the you know not h not not having
the user to tell you it sucks. It's it's
you know it's like two sides of the same
coin right. Well, you can't stay in that
period for too long because uh the
longer you are in the honeymoon, the
more goes your anxiety that what you're
building is actually something that
nobody wants. Yeah. Right. And so you
have to launch eventually to to get that
that feedback cycle or the flywheel uh
how Amazon calls it. Um uh and so both
of these things are true, but you're
right. You know, if if if you are able
to fund raise um based on reputation or
based on on the idea you have and so the
money question gets out of the picture,
then you have a certain period where
things are feel really good uh until you
have to launch and and then you you're
you're faced with the with the reality.
>> Yeah. with the reality of the app. So,
how uh I guess what can you say about
your sort of uh new startup uh on it and
maybe like again what made you sort of
take the leap from from uh from where
you kind of were uh in GitHub to this
world.
>> Yeah, I mean you know what made me take
the leap kind of explains where we're
going. Um look, you know, I started um
uh in be becoming a um company founder
in the developer tools space uh back in
2009. Uh uh I left my my job at at Bosch
uh uh in Germany, one of the big
automotive suppliers. Um uh building if
you have a car, you know, with
ultrasonic sensors in the in the bumper,
those are most likely from Bosch or one
two competitors.
>> And uh I left because I was so excited
about the the iPhone SDK and the app
store and I wanted to become, you know,
an app developer again after being in
automotive for for six, seven years. And
from being an app developer, I became,
you know, the startup founder of a
company called Hockey App that provided
a developer platform uh uh for mobile
app developers, you know, distributing a
beta apps u collecting crash reports and
feedback. And that company got sold uh
or we sold to that company in in uh in
late 2014 uh to to Microsoft. So it's
been now 11 years uh since I was last
startup founder. But ever since you know
my hockey app days, I have been in
developer tools. you know, hockey app
was a developer tool. Then I was at
Microsoft um together with NAD building
app center which was kind of like
bringing the pieces of Zamarind test
cloud and Zamarind insights together
with hockey app and we bought hockey uh
then we bought GitHub uh you know I was
uh VP of special projects at GitHub
before I became the CEO and through that
journey you know from mobile to the
cloud um to co-pilot and AI I have seen
how how software developers have have
changed the world and that the really
exciting thing I think is about being a
software developer is that as you're
building new products, you're constantly
also evolving how you do that. Um, and
you know, if I remember my first coding
uh uh uh exercises in the early 90s uh
first on a East German robot uh uh
computer and then on a Commodore 64 to
what software development today is like
it's it's fundamentally different. Like
if I would give my kids a Commodore 64,
they would probably, you know, figure
out how to play Diana Sisters or or or
something like that. but like typing
basic and it's like what the hell is
this user interface and where's my you
know where's my my copilot or my stack
overflow or or just Google to to look
things things up
>> the internet exactly the internet you
know the internet was open once you
started doing it you couldn't go back to
sort of developing without it
>> correct right and so if we we have
always had these moments where the
internet changed everything open source
changed everything mobile changed
everything the cloud changed everything
AI is also changing everything I
actually think you know we are still at
the beginning of that revolution. Now,
co-pilot started um more than four years
ago. You know, chat GPT came more than
three years ago. Last year was all about
chat and and agent mode and and this
year clearly it's all about full scale
coding agent, code review agent,
security agents. Uh but I still think
you know we are at the beginning of a
journey where the way the software
development life cycle works is going to
fundamentally change and that's you know
what I'm excited about and that's what
we're going to explore in my new
company.
>> Yeah, cool. Yeah, there's so much I
think the there's always like an
underestimating kind of a kind of
natural reaction, you know, when you
think about uh just sort of the scale of
the transformation, the
>> what's the sort of the uh the cliche is
that, you know, people uh overestimate
the short term and underestimate the
long term, right? In terms of the
potential of it. So, uh your survey,
>> it's really hard to predict, right? Like
if if we go back a year um uh into
December uh 2024, who would have
predicted that at the end of 2025
developers are back in the terminal,
>> you know, with with Cloud Code and and
Gemini CLI and Codex CLI and Coupile CLI
and have like six or eight or whatever a
grid of of terminals open and have all
these agents running in parallel and
trying to figure out, you know, uh how
to make that work with Git work trees
and how to merge all the results and how
to not have the agent delete all the
files on your computer or or the work of
of you know the last uh 30 commits
what have you and I think you know
that's where if anyone who's predicting
what that looks like in a year or two is
going to be fundamentally wrong and I
think that that's really what makes that
so exciting we don't know where we're
going other than that we do know that
we're going to keep building software
while maintaining you know billions if
not trillions of lines of code that are
already out there
>> yeah and that are growing and also like
you know kind of a part of the challenge
with the the tools so so there is like
I'm still reading though like there's a
fundamental conviction for like when you
make this move that a lot of the ability
to explore unencumbered is just sort of
better to do in in the dev space and I
guess from from a like uh it's
interesting to sort of see GitHub like
you know because as we as when I think
about innovation you know from
incumbents on it copilot is actually
like GitHub copilot is a very kind of is
a great example of innovation that came
from sort of within the company uh and
kind of like pioneered that sort of new
space of of of coding assistant that
feels like an AI tools now sort of you
know like the the old pattern but you
know for a while was there um and then
like even with all of all of its reach
and all of its sort of strength there
was uh like the opportunity for cursor I
guess kind of most notably to you know
copilot continue to thrive so it wasn't
really like at the expense of sort of
copilot but but but from a like a market
share perspective you know kind of grow
even faster right and sort of take up
that sort of space on it and then indeed
you have the disruption coming from
anthropic which is kind hard to think
about them. Are they a startup? Are they
incumbents? Like th those are very weird
beasts. The sort of the open AI and
anthropic that are like especially
anthropic like sort of a short-lived
organization and a massively valued uh
organization uh but still very much a
startup in uh in many ways. Um and you
know overhauls like the the fundamentals
of it's going to be terminal versus ID.
Um, so I guess there's a there there's a
sort of a a faith or still a perspective
that when you're looking to disrupt like
I I I believe that especially when
you're disrupting the way things are
done, not not just automating existing
workflows but rather sort of changing
the way that someone work those are
precisely the places where where it's
hard for an incumbent to kind of accept
it because they have all the power in
the existing way of working. uh and so
they you know it's sort of it's hard to
accept that that change will come right
>> I think that's the that's kind of the
outside in perspective and that you look
at you know companies that have been
leading uh for a long time and then
argue being disrupted or seeing more
competition and you you know feel sad or
worry about the people that are now kind
like in that position that they are no
longer the best in in the market. Um, I
think the inside out perspective is
often uh not as um dire as as you may
think. You know, um I I've often thought
when whenever for Mercedes uh that the
best thing that can happen to us is that
BMW announces a new model with a with a
new thing in it uh that the Mercedes
leadership didn't want to fund. And all
of a sudden you have an argument to get
to get the funding. Yeah. And and be
able to say, "Okay, look, our
competitors are doing this. we better
wake up and um and and and also you know
try to catch up again and you you saw in
the news that you know Sam Alman
declared a code red and Google had a
code red and I'm sure you know SA had um
or I not I'm sure I know SA had a bunch
of codes um over over his his tenure and
um and so competition is good it
actually makes uh business and it makes
life more fun and we see that everywhere
you know coming back to my Formula 1
example you know it was Red Bull that
won for four years and it was Mercedes
for like eight years and and that
bullhead had another four years. You you
kind of want these changes and it
motivates those that have been winning
for too long, you know, to come back and
then see how do we now transform our
organization to be a winner again. And
if you you mentioned cursor and VS code,
you know, actually the IDE space has
been phenomenally stable over the last
decade. Like I remember when I you know
started on a Mac I think was 2008 or
2007. I started on Textmate and and
Textmate was the revolution back then
and and then as text made kind of like
became stale and and text made 2 took
way too long switch to sublime edit h
and then VS code came in VS Code for the
last decade was the default uh editor
IDE for almost everybody. Um there's
obviously you know some EMAC users and
some Vim users and and what have you and
now we have you know real competition
again and it's not only cursor and VS
code with with copilot uh vinsurf is
obviously in the play now recently uh
Google anti-gravity came out uh there's
a kilo code and ko and zed and and so
there's a hu competition and that means
somebody sees an opportunity there to to
disrupt and to innovate and and
ultimately build a a sustainable
business and I think that really is
exciting and not something to to worry
about both as the incumbent and as a
disruptor.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I I I agree and I'm not
sort of worried about it. In fact, I I
like the changes. I think like a uh it
all of these require a moment of
disruption that sort of you know makes
sense that is that is hard for sort of
the incumbent to follow. And you're
right that it's always like competition
is the the greatest uh motivator uh for
it and the opportunity to drive. And at
GitHub, you know, it pushed us last year
in 2024 um uh uh to go from just provide
having one default model in copilot to
offering multimodel choice um uh where
you know at at GitHub universe in in
November October 2024 I announced that
we now back then you know support uh
claude oh what was even the version
number cloud3 I think um and Gemini 1.5
Pro and and in the meantime if if you
open cop um it has like a whole list of
uh uh u major models and then you can
bring your own model and connect open
router and all these kind of things
right so you can kind of see the direct
impact of competition in the market
leading leading to a better product uh
for the incumbent as well
>> yeah yeah that's actually really
interesting because I think one of the
big questions that is on GitHub we don't
have to sort of over rotate here on
GitHub but uh is is that you know GitHub
has kind of managed to be Switzerland in
many ways you know for a long time and
it's like hey we're going to work with
all these IDEs when all you know there
was VS Code but it's not a money maker
it's uh it's a sort of like a free
service to uh to the ecosystem. uh and
now with copi it's like a little bit
different like Microsoft you know as a
whole makes a lot of money from actually
being the sort of the provider of these
different models right and sort of and
and not the builder necessarily but the
sort of the uh the executor a lot of the
inference you know running on Microsoft
is a is a substantial
uh revenue source uh and uh and is
invested and so that sort of question on
sort of uh neutrality I guess or like
you know do you want to sort of play
nice with everyone as long as you use my
agent uh is a is an interesting it's not
entirely new like it existed in sort of
GitHub in other ways and like in the
apps in the sneak you know for instance
like in the app security as an example
um but it feels stronger now in terms of
that internal conflict uh to uh
>> well you know Switzerland Switzerland uh
also still wants to make money
[laughter] and all the companies there
and the countries none of this is like
critical it's just a change right it's
just a change
>> if you look at Microsoft um it is um
probably the uh uh biggest platform
company that is out there like it's not
only copilot and and GitHub that have
some form of you know neutrality
offering offering choice it's it's also
if you look for example on into Azure AI
foundry uh which has like a huge range
of models available so it's not just the
open AAI and the the Microsoft develop
models it's you know mistrial models and
black forest labs models and lots of
open source alternatives and you can
deploy your own model right so in that
sense um maybe the Switzerland analy
isn't as good as just saying uh it's a
platform company and platform companies
by design want to have as many players
on top of that platform you know which
is GPU inference as an example or or you
know CPU comput storage or what have you
in Azure um because that helps both you
know the platform provider as in
Microsoft and you know the partners all
to thrive
>> right I think that's really the the
leverage um that Microsoft has as a
business is the scale of of that
platform and that's the opportunity for
every startup to become I'm part of you
know Microsoft startup program and I
should ask you have you actually joined
the Microsoft startup program and
>> we're in the program but we're we're
sort of like in all the programs right
you know where uh because they all
commit until until you get
>> but you know at some point every startup
gets kind of especially every B2B
startup maybe less in B2C but B2B every
B2B startups comes to the point where
they either want to leverage Microsoft's
distribution channel and an amazing
enterprise sales team or or Amazon's or
Google uh because the scale of these
sales teams around the world and their
skill set is is so far ahead of what a
small startup can ever deliver without
going through the pain of you know
building out subsidiaries and building
out local offices and local meetups and
and and you know there's a lot of human
investment that has to happen that you
can't replace with AI because enterprise
sales fundamentally is still a you know
relationship uh relationship management
exercise
>> super valuable and the marketplaces and
sort of all of that and sort of access
to it I I think uh let me kind of veer
us off. You know there's like a world
that you and I can kind of geek out on
the business side. A little sort of make
us a little bit more technical here uh
on it. Uh and you know we were just sort
of established that it's hard to predict
but still let's sort of make some
predictions here. One of the things that
I love your opinion on is is kind of
like the scope of products in in the era
of sort of AI dev tools uh of it. Uh and
maybe uh the the the first one is is
just like the the delineation between
sort of reviews and kind of you know uh
collaborative interfaces maybe like the
GitHub interfaces. I guess we're sort of
still there but uh uh versus kind of
earlier on premise right we see uh uh
you can use agents locally you can use
agents that are sort of background
agents sort of the devins of the world
that will you know now there's a whole
variety of others uh that will that
you'll always kind of meet the code at
the PR uh to to begin with um and then
you see all the review agents you know I
had Merryill from Graphite kind of on on
the show here and you know we talked
about how, you know, they they're
adding, and that's true for everybody,
an ability to now interact, you know,
with the uh with the um uh the whatever,
like not just find a problem, but also
kind of fix it right there on the spot.
And there's the question, of course,
well, if you could find a problem at
that point, couldn't you have found it
uh beforehand on it? Yeah.
>> Um and a lot of the lines blur, you
know, a lot of the you know, where does
uh because automation is is much more
increased. And I'm curious like what's
your what's your lens when you think
about the the um the division of
products even between local devs and
sort of reviews and collaborative.
How do you how do you picture these
things uh evolving?
>> We always picture those things as
somehow collapsing into just one you
know unified stack or suite of products
or what have you. And I think the
reality then is that never actually
happens. And it's a bit of a pipe dream
uh of every you know head of engineering
or or engineering manager that they have
just this beautiful stack that everybody
in the company is using and and so you
don't have to uh worry about you know
outdated products or like conflicts
between one product does this and one
product does that you're buying multiple
times. So I think let's be real like the
you know there will always be uh you
know overlaps in in what companies do
and products do and there isn't like
this oneall solution. Um sometimes it's
you know purely based out of necessity
of you know moving from one tool to
another uh is is is is painful and you
rather not invest that time and the
literally the time and the money of your
engineers doing that just because you
want something completely standardized.
uh you're just accepting to some certain
degree I think to c to large degree
actually in engineering we will have to
uh accept that entropy always exists in
software and your software
>> and your stack always gets worse until
you invest time to remove tech debt. Um,
one of my jokes, you know, as as GitHub
CEO has been always that uh uh debt is
actually the wrong term because debt is
something you're supposed to pay off
over time. In in tech, we just refinance
into into the next big thing and then
there's always the next big thing and
before you know it, you have new debt uh
even though you just refactored from the
old debt into the new debt, right? So,
it's more of a refinancing.
>> In the business world, the word for debt
is leverage, right? You know, it's
[laughter] just a different lens over
there. It's it's you know it's it's it's
it's part of you know it's like similar
to uh your house in your kitchen that
you never get you never get out of the
mode of of putting the dishes into the
dishwasher and out of the dishwasher
unless you stop eating and then and and
then then you die and that's actually
true tool in software too unless you
stop you know uh building new features
into into software you're always going
to be in a state where you have to you
clean up um afterwards and and so if
coming back to your agent questions I
think you're going to see you know more
of a you know agentto agent
collaboration
Um so you mentioned graphite merl and
and you know the code review agent
what's really interesting about that
right now is it gives me as a human
feedback on code now but if that code
was written by Devon like why do you
give that feedback to me give it to
Devon right and have Devon figure out
like that that's how you would do that
in a in a in a humanto human developer
team right you would tell the two
engineers to work together until they
have reach stable state uh and then they
can come to me as kind of like the
manager of of of of these two humans or
the two agents to say, "Hey, we have
we're finished with our work." So, I
think there's going to be uh um you
know, you know, more we're going to see
more of that uh uh like the agents
working with each other uh to not make
the human the bottleneck uh within the
life cycle. Um, Simon Wilson on his on
his blog recently had like a statement,
I'm paraphrasing, um, but this was like,
we have to get comfortable with not
reviewing every single line of code
before we deploy them into production
because the sheer amount of code that a
single agent can write 24/7. Now, you
paralyze that into running 10 agents in
parallel all the time. you're just never
going to be able to review all that code
without the one human doing that
becoming the ma major bottleneck and
effectively erasing some of the
productivity gains from these agents.
And so you have to think about how do
you automate other processes down the
line to to be able to generate all that
code in the beginning.
>> I think one thing that's also like
underappreciated is that a lot of these
coding agents are actually uh really
good at brainstorming. Um and so a lot
of you know my developers are using
cloud code to write code but before they
do that they also use cloud code to
brainstorm uh uh with the agent um you
know to learn about a topic or about you
know some special API or what have you
or even implementation options right
like even a different
>> what are the other options yeah uh to
write you know an architecture document
um uh while you know everybody else in
in Australia is asleep and then and when
they when they can up you already have
something ready to share and so then
they can pick it up and and and and keep
working on this. I think there's and
again this is very human centric right
brainstorming you have to tell the agent
what you want to work on and I don't see
that going to be replaced anytime soon
like the idea still has to come from the
from the you know product manager or
engineer or you know founder um and the
how is is a iterative process with the
agent but it's not going to be replaced
by an agent making up the idea telling
another agent to implement it and a
third agent to review and deploy it
>> the agent to agent conversation is is uh
is one I I relate to and I think it's
still interesting when you think about
the dev tooling ecosystem to think about
who who does this right because you can
run claude code as all of these agents
right you can run you know any of these
whatever codecs right like you can run
that in the mode of you know like I
wrote the code and run it with another
persona in fact sub agents kind of do
that right like you are creating you're
you're delegating work or you're passing
along to some agent that has the right
context to represent expertise you could
choose different models on it. Uh but uh
but if they're if the agent is a is a
human, you know, often times like from a
from a company's perspective on it, it
might be one company, you know, that is,
you know, providing with the agent and
you're connecting it in all these
different contexts. Um so I guess one
thing I still so so I I relate to and
I'm curious about I don't know that we
precisely know what the flow is. What
are the interface points for us to uh to
engage with larger bodies of volume of
work? like review as a concept will
probably increase in importance because
you do less of the work. you review the
work of uh of AI but but a lot of the
current like software development review
activities maybe will go away and that's
not it's not just for that right it's
also like for testing it's also for you
know like I'm I'm just picking on that
as an example um and so I'm kind of
curious and almost like a little bit
concerned about a collapse of a lot of
these different tools and and the reason
I'm concerned about it is is your
comment before about competition right
is because you want you you don't want
it to just be the competition between
five giants, right? You want you want a
composable ecosystem, right? And in
which different uh pieces can kick in.
Um I don't know if it's like a comment
or a question that I'm sort of making
here, right? But I uh I guess you know a
little bit of like what are the right
delineations,
you know, for for a company.
>> It's more if you think about it, it's
more composable than ever though, right?
um like nothing stopping you um to use
cloud code today and Gemini CLI tomorrow
and and codeex on Sunday.
>> Yeah, very um there's there's almost no
switching cost. Same for the IDE uh same
for the code review agent. Um uh and and
again this goes back to um you know the
platform concept like the platform isn't
changing you're storing um your code on
GitHub or or GitLab or or Bitbucket um
or you know one of the you know few
alternatives that out there um but on
the agent side on the AI side everything
is composable and the space is moving so
fast that there's you know as we're
recording this yesterday GPT 5.2 2 came
out. Uh, and until that point in time,
everybody, you know, was talking about
Gemini 3 Pro being the best model. Now
we're kind of like figuring out is 5.2
now the best model. And by the time
maybe this part comes out, there's yet
another model and everybody's like, what
what the hell is Thomas and Guy talking
about about what the best model is? And
and then so as such, you know, there's
like almost no switching cost. And that
makes really this idea of I can compose
my pipeline uh on the best tools I have
available um so much more you know uh
realizable than than it was in the past
when you did have uh vendor login right
like if you built um your front end on
react uh there's really high switching
cost um to to go to a different uh
front-end framework when you're building
uh your CI/CD on on GitHub actions
there's really high switching cost
moving that away from to another CI/CD
provider so in many other parts of the
developer tool chain, we have high
switching costs, but in AI agents is
really really low and and that really
creates this competitive envir
environment where what was the best
thing six months ago may not be the best
thing now and whatever you know the best
thing is in six months nobody can
predict.
>> Yeah. I guess my my um I guess I would
challenge a little bit like you had this
sort of comment over there that like the
GitHub and GitLabs and Bitbuckets like
are still the place your store and like
it's just the agent that you play around
with. But I guess I would say that the
platforms are optimized for a type of
work. Uh and so you know the whatever
sort of uh infrastructure estate
management tools that existed pre-cloud
were not the right tools to manage a
cloud estate because in the cloud estate
software or like hardware was elastic.
you know, you could kind of spin things
out and and down and uh you know,
identity therefore of these machines was
different because you know, they were
short-lived and you know, immutable
infrastructure and all that. And you
know, now we have uh a different breed
of developers. The collaboration, you
know, as you pointed out, right, happens
between agents. And so what what type of
uh um uh tracking you know and it it's
hard to not think about git as that
because git is uh is like we're so it's
so ingrained you know and but I think
we're both old enough to have kind of
lived through subversion and sort of you
know like you know a bunch of this sort
of you know uh uh the places which sort
of get felt like a heresy and um and but
uh but you know fundamentally you're you
are uh uh versioning and storing and
collaborating ing uh on uh you know
between different methodologies right on
different competencies. Um, and I find
it actually really curious to think
about what is what is the right way to
version in and and and should it be and
maybe this is a part of where my sort of
pull request review I was like is pull
request even like the thing to to
represent anymore uh because you know is
that really the point of collaboration
uh between agents uh or or is there
something quite different right? I think
the question, you know, if we think
about these collaboration platforms
though, is do I still have to go there
to figure out what's the work that's
assigned to me, you know, what's my team
working on or do I head into a world
where I just ask my agent what's next,
you know, on my backlog or what's what's
guy working on? And so you're heading
into this world where you know the
>> your your your agent um or your
assistant if you will um becomes like
you know Javas to iron man and
effectively knows everything and and has
sub agents you know to access certain
skills. Yeah. And so you would basically
have your personal you know agent that
helps with travel booking and
calendaring and and has you know access
to your coding environment and all of a
sudden you don't actually open the
browser as much anymore
and open all these tabs and and all
these platforms. um where you know your
your leadership team told you this is
where your stack is um and that's why
you have to look for work um
>> and so I think this is you know but at
the same time there are still people
running cobalt for mainframes
>> and you know most of these cobalt
projects have no devops whatsoever they
don't use git you know they they don't
have CI/CD
>> they certainly have no sneak uh or or
test cases and test suites and and what
have you and and if you take that as the
most extreme example you'll realize that
as software developers we live on that
spectrum where on there's the really old
stuff that still powers you know huge
part of the banking industry of you know
the local and and and federal
governments and so on uh and in between
you have like you know people working on
Windows APIs uh for displays on on on on
train platforms uh uh Windows 95 APIs
not not Windows 11 API
>> but those are and and so you have that
spectrum and so yeah there is going to
be the kind of like state-of-the-art
developer that uses all these agents and
doesn't have to go uh into the web
anymore because all they can do is kind
of like talk into the computer like Mr.
Data and Star Trek and and gets the job
done. But in between now all the other
people that still need everything else
that we built in the last uh uh in the
last 30 years and and as such you know
that that is is really like a a gradual
change that's happening and it's not
this oh AI is writing 90% of all code
now and and we don't we don't need all
this old stuff anymore. I think is now
as as long as we are aware of when we
talking about how exciting these agents
are that in the middle there's like a
huge spectrum um of of other work that
still exists that engineers have to work
on. Uh I think you know it's both
exciting and also grounding uh uh how
how much work there is going to be for
for the next uh you know century to
come.
>> Yeah. Yeah. For sure. And and that
sounds very aligned with the sort of
it's more of a decade of the agent
versus the year of the agent, you know,
from Karpath's kind of quote on it. And
and it's true and you know, I kind of
sometimes say how like application
security companies are like cockroaches,
you know, they never die because because
technology never dies and you kind of
need to sort of secure all the way
these, you know, back to the middle
ages, right? You know, sort of uh uh you
know, you need to uh you need to provide
support for that and clearly none of the
new companies wants to sort of go there,
right? and the inevitable kind of growth
of any enterprise software company but
specifically you know for that make
>> you have to go historically right
[laughter]
>> I think you unintentionally made a bit
of a cynical statement about your own
company
so you could leave because I uh you know
first of all like I'm very happy for
sneak to be sort of uh you know immortal
and you know I'm uh happy with that but
it's no it's also like you just sort of
see I've been in I've been in ABSAC
actually for over a decade before I
started sneak and and sort of have seen
all these companies that you know just
they they came and they toned down but
they never went away uh because uh
because of those so so it's interesting
and I agree with you and I think
technology is very different I guess
kind of one topic to to uh to that that
I feel like this leads into is like as
individual as sort of the humans in this
whole kind of movie uh you know when the
cloud came along uh uh you
you know I guess you could kind of
appreciate that yes there's historical
ones and Maybe you made kind of a
version of a choice of like I'm going to
really specialize in this sort of
mainframe stuff uh because it's going to
be a big money maker and I'm going to
suffer but I'm going to make a lot of
money and uh and I'll sort of specialize
over there. I'm slightly cynical here or
maybe a lot cynical uh or or I can I can
go and immerse in the sort of new world
of cloud and and and and there was like
maybe a little bit more clarity at least
at some point around the skill set that
you need to therefore build uh to be a
cloudnative developer, right? to sort of
be you know a capable uh professional in
this new era and and AI is a bit more
murky than that. So like a bunch of
these predictions are you know beyond
their intellectual curiosity. I think of
course for you and I their bets around
as we build dev tooling companies you
know you have to you have to have a
theory of the future and then be very
adaptable that but you have to have a
theory of the future but then you know
for for so many more people you know
there's a question of like I'm a
developer what would my job look like?
What would be my competency uh in the
future? So I guess what what do you what
what's your view on that right? If
someone comes along and says so what
should I what should I get great at you
know what should I uh um what how do you
envision the job of a future AI native
developer?
>> Ever since I went to university I felt
like the you're actually never done uh
with with learning as a software
developer. um there there is no stable
state and those that feel like they have
reached stable state are ultimately are
planning for you know their retirement
either voluntary or involuntary um and
sure you know there is stuff that hasn't
changed much um uh like IBM mainframes
and cobalt code but I think you know if
you if you look into your company and if
you look into the world out there you
realize that that's not a growth
opportunity and the team is getting
smaller and smaller and and you start
working on more boring tasks and so yeah
you have stable state, you can be like a
specialist and maybe you can even you
know uh ask your boss for for higher
salary uh because uh the the boss will
have a hard find will have a hard time
finding uh college grads or university
hires that actually want to work on
cobalt. Um and um but that that stable
state ultimately is is is over the long
run not stable. It's just a gradual
decline until this this reaches zero or
like a you know marginal value and and
as such the biggest skill um as a
software developer as an engineer is
that you know how to learn uh uh new
stuff and and how to put this new uh
information in relation to what you're
currently working on because not
everything is actually as exciting as it
looks and and um there's also the danger
you're jumping you know on on the new
train um uh and and then you realize Oh
my god, you know this is actually
throwing us back two years. Like when
Apple released, you know, the Swift
language for the very first time, a lot
of developers were excited. And then
they realized moving their project from
Objective C to Swift, it wasn't actually
ready and it was slower and and the the
downloads all of a sudden was blown up
by like 100 megabytes or or whatnot. And
and and then you know there's many such
examples where just jumping on the new
technology isn't the right decision
either. And so having that skill, you
know, to learn and then to to judge, you
know, to apply your craft, um your
craftsmanship that you have learned over
the last decade or or so and ultimately,
you know, um taste to to say, okay,
we're going this way and and and not
that way. Um and then and I think this
is crucial even more so now with agents
is really what you could call
engineering skills like taking a huge
problem and of you know the huge problem
isn't as huge as building Facebook but
it's huge enough that you know uh you
don't know how long it will take you to
actually implement this and breaking it
down into into smaller into smaller
pieces
>> right all the way down to okay so now I
know what method and and unit tests I
have to have to write to actually
implement the the next the next
abstraction layer and I think that
engineering skill of you know
decomposing a big problem into into a
small problem then deciding you know how
to to split the work uh uh in your own
day and then with your other team
members that is even more crucial with
AI because only if you know what you can
offload to an agent and the agent can
actually implement efficiently uh and
what you have to do yourself then then
you gain uh productivity from AI right
like if you just try and error
everything here agent try this okay bad
try this again bad at some point, you
know, you could just go into the CSS
file and change the background color
yourself, right? And there's like some
oneline changes where it's like idiotic
to use AI if you know exactly where to
do that. And you might use AI to just
see how the agent fails with that and
you have a good you have a good post on
X or um uh but the reality is the
engineering skill set will be to know
when I can offload my work uh to an
agent or or you know work with a
co-orker and then have to do it myself.
But how so so I mean I I absolutely
agree with that today. But then what I
would challenge is, you know, if you're,
you know, a kid coming out of sort of
university right now, right? And and you
don't know that is the right sort of
domain to sort of really double down on
investing in getting good at that, you
know, and and sort of knowing how to get
down and know which lines in the CSS to
edit versus versus sort of spending that
the opportunity cost, right, of that
time learning how to maybe like uh
convey and sharpen, you know, like what
it is that you want to build, right? or
uh maybe even building like product and
sort of a uh and kind of a user
sensibility appreciation. So, you know,
kind of leveling up either towards the
kind of a a faster uh sort of
progression, I guess, for most people
towards the architect skills or into the
uh uh the more sort of a product
definitions or maybe some sort of new
nent uh uh profession. But I don't know
like feel feels hard for me to sort of
justify the time invested even even if
today you do you do um uh you do benefit
from having that type of depth of
skills. Or is it that the kids um
whether they go to high school or to
college actually learn how to use AI
much faster uh than you know the senior
or or staff developer that has already
been doing that for for a decade or two.
um you know if I look um into my kids in
school they have to you know submit
essays and uh funny enough you can
actually read the essays of all the
other kids as well and you clearly can
see who used AI to write it which I
actually think is is cool like kudos you
know to those kids that are like maybe
it was short before the deadline
>> and you know and then the teacher
probably can also see that this was
written with AI you know the the long M
dash and and and whatnot and
>> but they don't have the engineering
skills like they will embrace the AI
faster they have the engineering So like
should they lean into the engineering or
>> they're going next time they're going to
review the output and and prompt the AI
to build a version where the teacher
cannot detect that it came from AI,
right? And so as you as you I think in
many ways we should actually start in
very early like first grade or whatever
to teach our kids how to use AI in to
not cheat in a test but to actually
iterate, you know, and and and modify
the results and verify that the you know
when it talks about whatever the what it
actually says is is the right answer.
And so I think teaching kids that skill
of how to leverage AI uh to the best
possible outcome that is what you know
we we're going to see a new generation
um you know of AI native humans if you
will that in the same way that you know
if you look at uh what is it gen Z or
Gen Alpha grown up they have grown up
with smartphones and so for them using
you know uh WhatsApp and and signal and
and and chatting with their friends is
is totally natural and while you and I
when we grew up we had to you know make
a landline phone call. Um, and and then
you, you know, had the parents on the
phone and you kind of like had to pass
that first barrier of explaining to them
why it's now a good time for you to talk
with your buddy or, you know, even worse
with your with your future girlfriend or
whatever, right? And so like you you see
how the next generation is adopting
these techn new technology and
>> I think they have ultimately a better
life. There's there's challenges as
well, but like it's it's it's liberating
and democratizing and I think the same
will happen with AI and and everybody
will be able to learn coding. uh even if
their parents have no technical
background even a school is bad at
teaching it because they can just they
can just uh leverage you know the the
co-pilot or uh the chatpt that's always
there for them
>> and you know what and also doesn't judge
them and doesn't say you're stupid or
doesn't say you you should have learned
that three years ago right that's the
other thing that's really liberating is
that you can ask uh your AI assistant
any quote unquote dumb question and it
will keep answering until until you run
out of patience it will never run out of
patience
>> yeah I would little I want to sort of uh
stress a bit about the sort of the the
engineering skills like in in all of
that narrative which I fully buy into uh
they didn't necessarily need to know the
underlying you know when you get an
image from AI you don't need to know how
to draw to be able to sort of guide it
correctly you need to know what you want
uh uh better uh and and so with
engineering I feel like we get drawn
into this but you need to know how to
engineer that today that's true because
you're they're limited but in a decade
is that still true Um, and I I guess I I
get drawn a little bit more to like I
guess my biases are more about like know
what you want, which is actually pretty
darn hard, right? Like it's not a it's
not an easy thing to answer and then
know how to convey it and know how to
verify that it's been done correctly.
Uh, and to an extent let go of some of
your sort of coding chops to sort of
critique the AI's work or like do not
invest in improving those. Yeah,
>> I think we're already in that state
where um you mentioned the image example
um where you can easily also detect what
is AI slop um and at some point you're
just not going to go to that you know
substack anymore or you know um listen
to a presentation of all the uh AI all
the images as as poorly generated um
stuff and so that basically forces the
creator to get better at doing that and
in a way that's the new craft right of
learning how to use AI to get the better
output in for images that you know 10
years ago than the craft was to use
Photoshop or use use pencil and pen. But
of course, you know, you could have made
your same argument uh whatever 20 years
ago when Photoshop first came out that
it replaces the the you know artist that
that draws with pen and paper is
something that's very easier quote
unquote. uh except you know now there's
experts in Photoshop that are so much
better than you and I in Photoshop and
and so there's still there's still a
craft that exists and and that and and
we're going to see the same with AI.
There's those that are you know creating
amazing images uh with the help of AI
that that we cannot create without you
know learning how to do that. And if you
go if you take that back to software,
look, you know, the reality is um uh
commercial software projects uh and
their businesses ultimately have to
generate a profit in the long run. H and
ideally you have, you know, healthy
margins um or growing margins at least
um to to sustain that business. Yeah.
>> That's not going to work if you don't
understand what's happening behind the
scenes. And that's not going to work if
you don't have engineering and and
business skills, you know, to work with
these agents to create, you know,
ultimately a product that returns, you
know, enough money to pay the salaries
and and and a profit for the company.
And and so then the question really
becomes is who are the companies that
are fast enough to learn these these
engineering and business skills and who
are the ones who think they can get away
with you know just wipe coding
everything and and not paying attention
to this because those companies
ultimately will will run out of money
lacking competitiveness uh that they
they will not survive in the market.
>> Yeah. No, I love that you have to know
the insides to sort of innovate in it.
>> Um yeah like we can go on this for an
hour but I think we're sort of running
out of time on it. super excited to sort
of see what you build uh on it. Thanks
for all the insights here. If someone
wants to sort of follow your journey,
you know, when you uh share more about
uh your uh you know, your sort of uh
next evolutions of your company uh how
how can they follow you?
>> They can follow me on X um I'm Ash um
there and I'm also Ashtom or just my
full name on LinkedIn. uh in the in the
last few weeks have been a bit quiet as
we're working in STS on the on the new
startup but uh certainly more to come uh
throughout 2026.
>> Cool. Well, really excited to see what
comes out. Thanks again for sharing this
and thanks for everyone for tuning in. I
hope you join us for the next one.
>> Thank you so much, guy.